#### CONTACT

Montreal

514 914-1663

lucie.plantier@protonmail.com

github.com/lucie-pl

linkedin.com/in/lucie-plantier/

(𝚱) lucie-pl.github.io/

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Languages:

Ruby, Javascript

#### Front-end:

HTML, CSS, Figma, Bootstrap, Stimulus, React

#### Back-end:

Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

#### Cloud service:

Heroku

# Versioning tools:

Git, Github

#### Softwares and platforms:

Photoshop, Indesign, Mailchimp, Wix

#### LANGUAGES

French | English

# **LUCIE PLANTIER**

# **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER**

Enthusiastic and team-spirited with eight years of experience in marketing, communication, and event planning in the lively cinema industry.

Recently pivoted into coding through Le Wagon's Web Development bootcamp.

Known for my collaborative approach, I bring a strategic mindset and a blend of technical and creative skills to contribute effectively to web development projects.

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Cuisinator** - currently in progress

- Web app for me and my friends to gather and share cooking recipes, create our own categories and avoid ads or videos
- Stack: Ruby on Rails. React, PostgreSQL, Docker

## MotionExp.

- Mobile web app prototype for moviegoers to build watchlist and history list, rate movies, get notified when specific movies are programmed in cinemas near you, and chat with friends
- Designed and developed in two weeks
- Team lead in a team of 3, we used Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Bootstrap, Stimulus, Figma and Heroku
- Further developments planned: adapt it to work with an API, improve the friends features

#### E-Car

- Web application prototype that allows users to both rent electric cars based on their location, and offer their own vehicles for rent. E-Car is an Airbnb clone (marketplace).
- Developed in one week
- In a team of 3, we used Ruby on Rails, Cloudinary, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Bootstrap and Heroku

## **EDUCATION**

## Web Development, Le Wagon Montreal - Canada

10/2023 - 12/2023

- 9-weeks full-time intensive coding bootcamp
- Implemented and shipped to production a marketplace prototype,
- Designed and shipped to production a prototype of a mobile web app for moviegoers, MotionExp.

# Master in Marketing and communications,

Kedge Business School Bordeaux - France

09/2013 - 06/2017

# VOLUNTEERING & INTERESTS

**Organisations:** Project manager at Festival Européen du Court-Métrage de Bordeaux 2015 (1 000 attendees over 2 days of competition)

Sports: Running, tennis

Culture: Movies, series

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

# Communication coordinator. Montreal - Canada

Cinémas Beaubien, du Parc, du Musée (02/2019 - 09/2023)

Working in close collaboration with top management, and leading a team of two, I was responsible for all external communications as well as the partnerships' development for the three cinemas.

- Designing communication plans for the overall activities of the cinemas, and reporting them to the general management
- Establishing partnerships with strategic cultural organizations and building strong commercial relationships with the business ecosystem
- Timely follow up on the KPI and revising strategy as and when required

# Executive assistant, Paris - France

mk2 Cinémas (07/2017 - 07/2018)

In one of the top 3 largest cinemas in Paris (1.5 million admissions/year, with up to 11,000 spectators/day), I was leading a team of 40+ operators. My mission was to ensure the smooth running of the cinema, delivering increased commercial performance and an optimal customer experience.

- Acting as an interface between management and operational team to ensure smooth implementation of new tools and processes
- Analyzing daily KPIs in terms of attendance and deploy relevant action plans
- Responsible for the full HR management cycle: recruitment, ressource scheduling, training and performance monitoring

## Marketing & communication assistant, Paris - France

SND - Groupe M6 (01/2017 - 06/2017)

Elaboration and implementation from A to Z the promotional strategy for theatrical releases on the French market. Worked on the following films: La La Land, Lion, Les As de la jungle, Ôtez-moi d'un doute, Seven sisters, You were never really here

- Define, plan and execute the purchase of advertising spaces to ensure an effective promotional campaign (print, radio, web)
- Managing and following up on media and non-media partnerships (up to 10 partners per film release)
- Organizing and planning the logistics of major events: press day, previews, international talent, internal screenings at M6

# Project manager assistant, Paris - France

mk2 Agency / mk2 + (09/2015 - 02/2016)

Within MK2 agency, part of the MK2 group, I was in charge of events, mostly B2B, within the network of MK2 theatres (both public and private).

- Building commercial proposals in line with client briefs (budget from 2.5k up to 200k€ per event)
- Ensuring the administrative follow-up of client files, the timely operational implementation of the events and the relations with the various service providers (technical, caterers, valet parking, hostesses/hosts, furniture)